[Music]
hi John can you hear us Hi how are you
I'm great how are you great thanks for
having me never a problem always welcome
sorry it's under these circumstances me
too me too so um you know you have a
very unique perspective on the current
situ with Julian Assange and the
possibility the possibilities that he
faces should he be expelled from the
embassy I just want to kind of open the
floor to you and just ask for your
sentiments or thoughts on the latest
developments and what could come
next I'm actually not as pessimistic as
I was 24 hours ago um 24 hours ago I
thought well this is this is what we've
been fearing all along it's finally
going to come to pass and now we have to
come up with a strategy but the more I
thought about it today and I thought
about it all day
today I thought this is actually the
perfect time for us to make that
argument that Julian is a journalist
Julian is a publisher uh Julian is not
the kind of person that the Espionage
Act was written for he's not a spy he's
a working journalist doing his
job uh my co-host on myo radio show
Brian Becker said
today let's look at the New York Times
The Washington Post CNN Fox M MSNBC
they're often wrong and sometimes
they're very wrong Wikileaks has
literally never been wrong that's
journalism you don't see Wikileaks
having to issue Corrections or apologies
or retractions because they're never
wrong that's just simply journalism so
if the US government has made up its
mind that it wants to extradite Julian
and charge him with these very serious
felonies and I I still hold out some
hope that that's not the
case maybe we need to start thinking
about issues like jury
nullification
where we can influence a jury especially
a jury in a very highly educated area
like Washington
DC so that regardless of what the law
says regardless of how the law is
written regardless of what the
prosecutors are going to tell a jury
that jury will go into its Jury Room and
will conclude that the law is just
simply
wrong and so it doesn't matter what the
law
says you know I say all the
time that when I was at the
CIA the culture was such that we were
always taught that everything is a shade
of
gray and in many cases that's just
simply not true some things are black
and white they're right and wrong this
is just
wrong and I think that there are enough
people out there who are going to agree
that this is wrong this is political
it's a
vendetta uh the deck has already been
stacked and uh and they're just not
going to stand for it so I feel a lot
better about this today than I did
yesterday I maybe I'm crazy maybe I'm
naive but I still actually feel like I
can put my faith in the in the jury
system provided that the jury is able to
get the information necessary to make a
just
decision now that is a huge caveat that
I think is it cannot be um overstated um
the accurate information that they would
have to receive and on previous visuals
you've mentioned that uh the fact that
if Assange is extradited to the US and
if he's prosecuted uh prosecuted he will
very likely not have any access to the
information and evidence used against
him even his lawyers would have very
little access to that and that's an
issue that I wanted you to comment on
further this evening because I've seen
so many supporters of Julian sandre
Wikileaks who tell me oh bring him to
the us so that he can have a fair trial
and get the evidence out into the public
Arena and I always respond with your
quote about that so please explain to
the audience again what would be the
reality if you were to arrive in the US
in a national security case especially
in the eastern district of Virginia
which is where Julian apparently would
be tried uh there is no such thing as a
fair trial we have a law here in the
United States called uh sipa the
classified information protection act
and what that means in Practical terms
is that if you've been charged with a
national security crime where you are
accused of having exposed most
classified information what the
government calls National Defense
information you are just simply not
permitted to to offer that information
up in your own defense in
court there's a process by which the
prosecutors can do it they can
declassify it solely for the purpose of
Prosecuting you and that's what they did
in my case they said we have
Declassified this information solely for
the purpose of Prosecuting Mr kiraku
they would do that with
but they wouldn't declassify enough
information for him to actually defend
himself they would declassify only that
information necessary to prosecute him
and so when the justice department
invokes CPA the classified information
protection act what they do is they
literally clear the courtroom of
everybody but the
prosecutors the defense attorneys and
the defendant the judge the clerk and
the court reporter that's it the
courtroom is empty and then they bring
in a technical team to come and sweep
for bugs and at that point Julian's
attorneys would make a motion or as in
my case 70 motions to declassify the
documents necessary for Julian to mount
a
defense in my case we had blocked off
two days for these hearings two full
days we walked into the courtroom uh
sippa was invoked the courtroom was
cleared and they they literally they
physically locked the door and then the
judge said I'm going to save everybody a
lot of time and I am going to deny all
70 of these motions she said you just
simply do not need this information to
defend yourself and then that was it and
so as we were walking out of the
courtroom I said to my lead attorney
what just happened in there and he said
we just lost the case that's what
happened he said we have no
defense and it was true I said now what
do we do he said now we talk about a
plea and so my point is that that's not
Justice not at
all
that's Washington area Justice that's
National Security Justice you know
there's an old Richard prior joke that
you go to court you're looking for
justice and that's what you find just
us right and that's what I fear is going
to happen with uh with Julian Julian's
going to end up in the eastern district
of Virginia looking for justice and the
only the only thing that's there is just
us outside with our signs demanding that
he get a fair trial that'll never come
and that's why I think we need to fall
back again on this issue of jury
nullification and jury nullification
would not be possible could not be
successful unless our voices are heard
right right look at it this way
a jury consultant actually quite a
famous jury consultant he was the jury
consultant for the OJ Simpson case and
for the uh the Trayvon Martin case and
and William Kennedy Smith he was my jury
consultant and he told me if you were in
any other District in
America I'd say let's go for it we're
going to win this thing but the eastern
district of Virginia your jury is going
to me be made up of people
who are members of or who have relatives
who are members of the CIA the FBI the
defense department the Department of
Homeland Security and intelligence
Community
contractors you don't have a chance is
what he told me
well in my case he was right in Julian's
case I think that's wrong because Julius
is famous enough or inFAMOUS enough
depending on what side of the issue you
fall on that He commands attention in
the media we can use that ability to
attract attention to turn the debate so
that our voices are heard saying over
and over and over again that Julian is a
journalist and that Wikileaks is a
journalistic
organization all we need is one juror to
agree with us
one and then it ends
how do you how would you advise our
audience and you know participants in
this vigil to bring that type of
possibility about should s should a AR
be extradited to the US you know what
can we do to make those our voices heard
on that a lot of things I think for
those of us who have the ability to um
to get published we need to write like
we've never written
before agree more on that yeah yeah and
not just for you know
for those Outlets that we're so
comfortable with where we all just sit
around agreeing with each other uh you
know reader supported news Consortium
news truth dig truth out we need to get
out there into the Wall Street Journal
and the Washington Post and the New York
Times and the Washington times we need
to form alliances with conservatives
because you know the the the ideological
spectrum is not a straight line it's a
circle and there's a point where the
right and the left meet and that is
where civil liberties are involved
and so we need to form a strategic
alliance with those on the right who
love civil liberties those Li
Libertarians who understand that the
constitution was written to protect
people like Julian Assange and
organizations like
Wikileaks so we need to write and those
of us who don't write or can't write or
get published or whatever need to be not
just in the streets but in front of that
Courthouse you know that as soon as
Julian arrives in the United States
every news Outlet in America is going to
be in front of that courthouse and
they're going to be broadcasting all day
every day we need to get in front of
those
cameras look you know juries are going
to be warned not to read articles about
the case not to watch TV about the case
this is going to be such a high-profile
case that that's going to be
impossible and so absolutely they are
they are going to hear what we have to
say we just have to keep up the pressure
and let me let me backtrack a little bit
too you know it it's not over till the
fat lady has sung and so we need to
exert as much pressure as we possibly
can on the Ecuadorian
government uh they cannot be allowed to
get away with this this nonsense forgive
me I haven't watched the last uh the
last six hours but this this nonsense
that that they may try to argue that
they've somehow negotiated the notion
that Julian wouldn't face a death
penalty charge this isn't a death
penalty charge in any case Under the Sun
the only way this would be a death
penalty charge would have been if the
United States was in a state of declared
war which we haven't been since December
8th
1941 and Julian were caught uh providing
Aid and comfort to the enemy so don't
treat us like we're stupid and that we
somehow think this is a death penalty
case this isn't a death penalty case
what this is is this is a case of the
ecuadorians being sellouts this is a
case of the ecuadorians wanting American
money and more favorable trade uh
uh negotiations or debt Rel debt relief
right whatever it is visas who knows uh
this is about lenan Moreno being a a
two-faced Trader I hate to say it this
is a guy that we put our trust in which
was very foolish uh and so we have to
stand up to the Ecuador
and uh and make sure that they
understand that this is this is not
acceptable currying favor with the Trump
Administration or even the Obama
Administration before it it's just not
going to go it's not going to fly
absolutely and I do want to remind our
audience that your refer of your
reference to the fact that you know at
the beginning of of uh his
administration and and when he was
running for for office Wikileaks
supporters were were fully behind Maro
because he was viewed as the successor
to Korea who would protect Assange so
just in case some viewers weren't aware
of that yeah that's exactly
right and I think that that has been one
of the elements of this whole scenario
that has been so shocking and and you
know you say it's a great you know
sentiment that you know we're not stupid
that that the death penalty issue is is
you know is a lack but you know the same
can be said absolutely about all of the
allegations that Lennon bro has made
against jul Assange and this thisa paper
Scandal it's ridiculous had to laugh out
loud today when I read this this article
in CNBC where Moreno made the the
requisite accusations about about the
leak of the papers and which was just
simply factually not true right this
came from a legislator in the Ecuadorian
uh uh Parliament but then he complained
that Julian somehow uh photographed his
food and his daughter's dancing and the
interior of his bedroom and it's like
buddy you're confusing Julian with the
CIA the CIA is bugging your bedroom and
taking pictures of your kids and your
food not Julian
Assange he doesn't even have internet
access like he's he's the one person in
the world who couldn't hack anybody
right now right yeah right and Moreno is
the one that knows that more than anyone
of course it's all a lie it's all a lie
and it's all to twist public opinion
well we can do that too we can fight
back
too absolutely and I think it's great a
great point that people who maybe are
not published or who don't write uh you
know use their bodies to show up you
know use your
bodies and if you're not in the
Washington area by God go on Facebook
and Instagram and Twitter you have
friends you have relatives you have
followers make sure that they know your
position on Wikileaks and Julian Assange
and try to convince them of of the
justice of this
cause you know this is one of those
I I really don't believe that I'm
overstating this this is one of those
once in a generation events like like
sacko and venetti or the rosenbergs
where we really do need to pull together
and point out an injustice and fight to
correct it I couldn't agree more I
actually had a very similar conversation
before this vigil began saying exactly
the same thing this is one of those
moments where we you choose what side of
History you're on and a decade a
generation from now people will be
looking back at this I think similarly
to the way that they've looked at you
know Susie Dawson's example of the
Nelson Mandela uh support and movement
the Civil Rights Movement things like
that where there is this really clear
demarcation between right and wrong yes
and this is on the side of right and as
you say people should be convincing
their friends and family of that for
sure I I think that's it right
there so uh what c i from your
perspective as somebody who was you know
a CIA analyst can you describe to us
maybe uh you know some of the the from
your perspective the way in which this
these allegations from Moreno have been
AAR and or just the way that that the
the kind of psychological warfare that
has been waged against the public uh
when it comes to Assange which is why we
don't see the equivalent of the yellow
vest protests which have gone on for 20
weeks with thousands and thousands of
people participating we don't see that
at the Ecuadorian Embassy so you know if
you could comment on on that
psychological warfare that has achieved
that uh that would be I think fantastic
to hear
sure you know I think that
operationally it's better for the CIA
the longer Julian remains in the embassy
the CIA doesn't care about prosecutions
the CIA cares about sending a message
the message is we have kept this man in
what is in effect solitary confinement
for the last six and a half years and
there's nothing he can do about it the
FBI sure they care about about
prosecutions because that's how they get
promoted for the CIA it's about making
an example of
people in my own
case the the point wasn't to see how
many years in prison I could get the
point was to frighten anybody else who
was even considering blowing the whistle
on waste fraud abuse or illegality it's
the same thing with Julian you know
Julian did something that worked he
created something that actually worked
um he created something that actually
protected its
sources and that actually
exposed war crimes and crimes against
humanity and so they had to make sure
that that
ended so what do you do when you're
confronted with someone that you need to
make an example of who has taken up
residence uh in a in an embassy
belonging to a country that's actually a
weak
country then you start using some muscle
and that muscle in this case is economic
you know it's like it's like Lenin
Moreno thinks that nobody reads nobody
Among Us reads the Wall Street Journal
that we didn't see the article about how
he practically got on his knees and he
begged the Trump White House for an
increase in both uh uh us aid aid and uh
uh better tariffs so that they could
export more Goods to the United States I
read the Wall Street Journal I saw that
article um this guy's supposed to be a
communist he's supposed to be a a a you
know Liberator and and uh and somebody
who values human rights and civil rights
and civil liberties and he's not it's
all about the
money so it's hard sorry it's hard
to it's hard to confront the US
government when it's not acting in a
case like this as a monolithic
organization the CIA has its own uh
interests the FBI and the justice
department have its own interests and to
tell you the truth I think the White
House and even the Department of State
being led by Mike Pompeo have their own
interests uh and so we have to fight
them individually along with fighting
the
ecuadorians yeah you know also remember
there are there are a lot of us
uh from all around the world I mean how
many people watch these visuals it's
thousands and thousands of people every
time I do one of these I'm flabbergasted
by the number of people around the world
who actually sit and watch these and
comment on them well that tells me we
have a lot of soldiers on our side as
well and so if they believe that it's
time to squeeze this pimple we can be
there squeezing
back absolutely and I think uh to your
point about the fact that they're not
just seeking a prosecution but they're
trying to make an example of people like
Julina Sange of yourself of Chelsea
Manning I think that that is is really
the principal reason that you don't see
a flood of of people following you
following Chelsea Manning in the same
sense or in an analgous sense to the way
that you see maybe a flood of of women
coming forward in the after in the
Weinstein Scandal when one woman comes
forward and says this happened to me and
the other woman women that know about
that and also experienced it flood
forward I think what you're describing
is exactly why we don't see that and a
New York Times Reporter told me that on
the day of my arrest every National
Security Source that the New York Times
had went completely
silent that's exactly what they wanted
to
happen no question I just think the
impact of that can't be overstated and I
think that that point needs to be needs
to be made to people that there are
other people like yourself that are
within these agencies that have a
conscience but that have been scared and
and terrorized into Silence by these
examples especially when the uh the
oversight system doesn't work you know I
use Tom Drake as an example all the time
I'm gonna do it again Tom Drake did
everything perfectly by the book he did
everything the way we're all taught to
do if you witness evidence of waste
fraud abuse illegality or threats to the
public health or Public Safety you go to
your immediate supervisor if you don't
get satisfaction there you go to your
supervisor's supervisor and then to the
Inspector General and then the general
counsel in the case of NSA being a
Department of Defense Agency you then go
to the Department of Defense uh
Inspector General If You Get No
Satisfaction there you go to either the
house or the Senate uh oversight
Committee in that case the intelligence
committee that's EX exactly what Tom
Drake did and he was charged with nine
felonies including seven counts of
Espionage when he never ever provided
classified information to any
journalist but it doesn't matter
because even though even though the
charges against Tom were all dropped the
government declared Victory because they
ruined him and they made an example of
him so it silenced anybody else at NSA
who was thinking of going forward Ed
Snowden said that without Tom Drake
there would have been no Ed Snowden
that's the exception rather than the
rule no question at all I think that the
um especially and now not only with Ed
Snowden and his you know um being
stranded in Russia I I can't imagine the
people that are inside these agencies
that would want to come forward and what
they would consider you know in in um
you know weighing that measuring that
choice and basically giving up their
entire lives for that moral decision but
um so yeah so what can the public
audience do to support people who or
support um not only the whistleblowers
who have come forward and who have been
prosecuted and persecuted as a result
but also the potential for others to
come
forward well one of the things is to
participate in events like this uh this
has such a broad
reach that you know it's a events like
this that make wouldbe whistleblowers
know that they aren't alone that there's
a community that supports them and would
automatically uh come to their aid so
that helps a lot and like I said a few
minutes ago be active on social media
pushing this narrative uh there's
something that's actually a little more
practical too uh and that is we need to
start thinking about raising some money
uh for Julian's defense
there
are some lawyers in Washington there are
a half a dozen that come to mind just
off the top of my head who are legal
Titans in this
city and they are the best attorneys
money could buy uh there are a couple in
particular who are great if you're
guilty and you want to negotiate the
best deal there are a couple who are
great if you're innocent and you want to
go to jury and you want to win this
thing so we need to think about getting
Julian the best legal team that money
could possibly buy this is not a case
where you need one or two attorneys to
go up there and read their speeches and
you know object and do whatever it is
attorneys do we need a team of a dozen
of the best legal Minds in Washington
and I think we're rapidly approaching
that absolutely and I've just been um
busily grabbing the uh link to the
defense fund of jul Assange and the page
where people can donate and I've just
thrown that in into chat just on that
note because yeah I think that you know
there there are a number of different
ways that you can uh donate to WikiLeaks
and you know you can go to wikileaks.org
you can buy from their shop but of there
are there is this separate site uh
justice for Assange tocom where that you
can donate specifically uh to assange's
Legal defense which as you point out is
critical at this time I'm gonna go on
the site right now as we speak okay yep
there it
is if you want we could go there and I
can share a screen just to show people
what it looks like yep I'm on
wikileaks.org the other one tell me the
other one again it's Justice for the
number for Assange
a legitimate website one second
good okay so here we see this page this
is the justice for ass.com website the
homepage is over here but this is
specifically the Donate page so this is
It's really as simple as that you just
click to donate uh the the website in
general though has a lot especially for
independent journalists has a lot of
information that is incredibly useful
and that you never see an establishment
press um it's so I would urge people to
not only donate but to explore this
website and use it as am use the
information in in sites like this as
ammunition in the fight to correct the
record when it comes to a Sange because
you know it's a wealth of information
that is just waiting to be used so but I
will end the share screen but I just
wanted to show people that so they know
that this isn't some sort of scam yep
excellent that's what we
need yeah I think that that that point
can't be made enough I think that we
definitely don't we don't emphasize
donating um too much because obviously a
lot of people out there in the public
are struggling you know financially and
all of that but I think that we can't
just leave that by the wayside either we
have to encourage people to make that
concrete tangible donation um you know
and people do ask like what can I do I
feel powerless um I want to support them
but I don't know how and if you don't if
you feel unable to express your voice
then that is one way uh donating is
definitely a way
to financially kind of raise your
voice and you know looking at the uh at
the Wikileaks shop too there's a whole
lot of cool stuff on there go ahead and
spend 10 or 20 or $30 it's all for a
great
cause absolutely I I I think that uh
some of the the sentiments of uh people
like Caitlyn Johnstone and yourself I
feel like we need to somehow crowdsource
uh you know making that into um you know
stamped like a sentiments that are on
things like mugs shirts etc etc and
raise money that way but that was
literally an off the cuff IDE had
earlier today but um but yeah I think
that yeah go ahead at the at the CIA we
used to sell coffee mugs that that
were on the coffee mugs they said admit
nothing deny everything make counter
accusations and it was kind of a joke
but it was kind of not a joke and they
were by far the most popular coffee mugs
in the whole place everybody had them on
their desks we could do the same thing
here and use that money to buy the best
lawyers in Washington for Julian there
would be nothing better than to have
that actually work and to do that I
think uh I think it's really interesting
that whole concept of plausible
deniability just summed up in a mug that
people are actually buying that's
hysterical well I'm glad that you and
and our last guest Margaret Kimber both
um in in a positive mood I think that
that that that's the absolute best state
that we can be in right now uh as we
watch things unfold and as we really do
hope not just based on like Blind Faith
but as we really hope that the attention
we are collectively bringing to this
issue will make a difference and protect
Assange from being expelled from the
embassy and hopefully would make a
difference in in any prosecution that
might happen down the road I was
heartened this morning and Joe laori and
I discussed this actually I was
heartened
when I saw the Ecuadorian government um
back off a little bit saying that no no
decision had been made the information's
not correct I think a decision had been
made I think the outcry was so great
that they were taken aback by it and uh
and so they had to put the breakes on
things and to me that's that's exactly
what we need to be doing it worked yeah
and thank you for raising that point
because I think that there is a danger
after a immediate response like this
vigil and you know the Press
congregating outside the embassy and all
of that you know some people whether
they're trolls or Earnest whatever they
will accuse Wikileaks and the rest of us
of engaging in like a a boy who cried
wolf scenario but I think you've just
answered that in that you know really
it's not that at all it's the fact that
this response has prevented the plan
that had been in place from from
happening I think so I think
so and I think that if it's only this
continued response that will continue to
prevent it from happening so what you
know this vigil will end on Monday or
late late on Sunday what should we all
be trying to do in the the days after
the vigil ends and to make sure that the
eyes remain on the embassy and we don't
just allow this to happen like next
weekend instead of this weekend for
example yeah um you know I think that
that this notion of taking to the
streets we need to begin it now and not
let up we need to at least here in the
Washington area we need to be picking
the Ecuadorian Embassy uh downtown here
and we need to be writing and giving
interviews and talking and we can't let
people forget about Julian's predicament
we can't we can't let people forget that
that his freedom is hanging by a thread
here and it's going to be decided by who
knows people behind closed doors in the
you know the dark Halls of the
intelligence Community or the federal
law enforcement Community we just have
to keep shouting and pushing and and
making sure that this stays in the news
finally there was some mainstream press
coverage you know it's a shame that it
had to be bad news that brought the
mainstream media out but maybe we can
still capitalize on
that absolutely and I think that another
example of that success is is the fact
that Chelsea Manning although she is
still imprisoned and very unfairly
imprisoned she has been uh you know
taken out of solitary confinement and I
think without the efforts of her support
te support team and the Legion of
supporters who um raised their voices in
her defense I don't think that that
would have happened I think you're
you're absolutely right yes so I think
that that and I think it's something
that you know we discussed with margar
earlier that is an example of the fact
that the the you know the voice is
raised in support aren't just blowing
Into The Wind that that it does make a
difference but um you know do you have
any other um you know issues that you
think need to be discussed for example
the fact that uh just the fact that so
few journalists in establishment press
and I know that this is an issue that's
been talked to death to some extent but
so many journalists are not standing up
for Assange they're engaging this
propaganda war against him against their
own interests is there anything that
will make them wake up to the reality of
this situation I'm not sure to tell you
the truth and I think I think that
that's because of the the Takeover of
the American Media by uh corporate
interests you know almost no Outlets
have a budget for example for
investigative journalism anymore you
have to turn to the likes of of
propublica
or well I hate to even say it but the
intercept uh and Wikileaks for real
investigative journalism so I think
think that uh that by and
large
mainstream uh journalists either don't
have the
wherewithal or the fire in the belly
necessary to cover these important
issues I think that they're told what to
cover and they're largely content doing
that the C yeah no well actually the CN
I remember recently uh in the result in
the wake of the Mueller uh report you
know fur or uh I believe it was an
editor from CNN said we're not
investigators we we're reporters and
that that it was admitting that exact
point so
ridiculous
absolutely so but uh yeah oh go ahead if
you're gonna say something I was gonna
say that's why it's always such
Blockbuster news when they come up with
something that's mildly interesting
because now investigative journalism is
so rare that that that journalism in and
of itself is news that's the sad State
we're in it's extremely sad and it's
been monopolized and controlled uh for
for by so so few people you know you've
got pets like the Washington Post owned
by Jeff Bezos contract with the CIA etc
etc you know it's it's mind-numbing the
degree to which the media is not the
media it is just mouthpieces of power
so
but well I know that uh the initially
when Julina sand was silenced last year
just over a year ago by Ecuador um you
delivered a number of petitions to the
Ecuadorian Embassy I believe in DC um
yes do you have any are there any plan
if you're willing to share it are there
any plans to do similar uh a similar act
uh in result uh in the result of the pre
uh recent news from Ecuador or uh we
haven't discuss when I say we I mean
those of us from veteran intelligence
Professionals for sanity haven't
discussed it in the last two days but
yeah the time is ripe we need to do it
now like this weekend immediately and
I'm happy to take the lead on that uh
that's what we did last year we wrote a
letter to the Ecuadorian uh president uh
through the Ecuadorian Embassy here in
Washington we had something like three
or four dozen signatures of uh retired
intelligence professionals from CIA NSA
FBI Homeland Security and the uniformed
military and Military Intelligence
servic
uh so we like to think you know we're a
group of people who know what we're
talking about we were received very
warmly in the in the Ecuadorian Embassy
here in Washington uh I like to think
that the letter had some some impact I'm
not sure but at the very least it didn't
hurt and as you said yeah now is the
time to to do it again with even more
support and more
signatures well I I wish you all luck in
in delivering that and writing that
because I think it is it is important
it's another way of raising our
Collective voices and you know speaking
of VIPs and Veteran intelligence
Professionals for sanity um I remember
uh when Gina haspel was nominated CIA
director by Trum uh by Trump you and
other VIPs members wrote very
vociferously against that nomination and
I bring that up because I want to ask
you to explain to our audience you know
not I don't I'm not asking you to go on
a rant against Trump like a political
like statement but I just want to ask
you to explain to the people that really
do support Wikileaks and Assange but who
think that Trump will bring him to the
US and pardon him or you know free him
or have a fair trial can you please
explain to them how the nomination of
people like Gina haspel Elliot Abrams
John Bolton Etc show a different picture
than they seem to think
exists that point I think is probably
the most important but I I will tell you
this I actually have some access to the
White House right now um also yeah I
yeah I I do it's quite expensive access
but it's access
nonetheless enough of that uh with my
point being one of the the most
important things I've learned in this
whole process of trying to gain access
to the president is that the president
really is
malleable the thing is is and this is
just his personality he needs to hear
something from three different people if
he hears from Elizabeth Voss that juli
nange ought to be pardoned he's not
going to pay five seconds of attention
to you if he hears it from you and from
me he's still not going to pay any
attention but if he hears it from the
two of us and somebody that he plays
golf with at maral laggo on the weekends
he might actually do something and so
you remember as as well as I do when he
said during the campaign and I quote God
bless
Wikileaks right who knows maybe maybe
he's willing to be um uh convinced uh
now you raised something that I think is
critically important uh and that is the
list of what I believe to be very very
dangerous neoconservatives appointed to
some of the most important national
security positions in government uh he
was clearly influenced by other neocons
in those in those uh nominations and so
if he can be influenced one way I
believe actually that he can be
influenced in another way as well it's
just a question of getting to him now we
can't pick up the phone and call Donald
Trump but we can continue to write and
to shout and to try to influence people
who do have access to Donald Trump you
know there are a lot of Republicans out
there who
support Wikileaks and who support Julian
if not for uh his his position on civil
liberties then because they view him as
an opponent of Hillary Clinton's I don't
care why people support Julian so long
as they support him I don't care what
their what their basis is just so long
as the outcome is is right so maybe we
actually do have a chance
here that is the most optimistic and and
positive um take on that that I could
possibly imagine I think you know my uh
thoughts going into that that question
were you know very kind of pessimistic
negative right yeah exactly like there's
no hope that that that Trump would
change his mind on this this issue but I
think you it is a really great point
that he obviously is malleable since he
has flip-flopped on Wikileaks thus far
at least once he has he's flip-flopped
on Wikileaks and I I think that's a good
thing you know um an aid to Trump um
mentioned me to him about six months ago
and um he paid no attention whatsoever
but then ran Paul mentioned him to me
mentioned me to him about two weeks
later and he said you
know Joe Smith mentioned this guy to me
a couple of weeks ago so now that's two
people so I know that this is true what
I've been told that he needs to hear
something from three different people
three different people he
respects and he's willing to change his
mind that is the most optimistic thing
I've heard all day and I think that
that's really that should should
motivate the Republican and Trump
supporting audience to get out there and
raise their voices exactly right yeah
the only problem I see the only problem
I see is that there H there is a
quadrant of those people that have been
pacified by things like hon and other
other uh thought patterns where they
believe that they don't have to do
anything that Trump is in control and
he'll save the day right that has to be
kind of addressed in order to get them
fired up to try to change his mind yes
because that's just simply not true um
and that that weakens us if people
believe things like Konan yeah that
weakens us but we need to get to the
likes of Mike Lee Republican senator
from Utah or Rand Paul a republican from
from Kentucky or Mark Meadows who's the
chairman of the the house tea party
caucus we need to get we need to get
close to Republicans who believe that
this is a civil liberties issue and not
a criminal one they're the ones who can
really influence uh the
president much much more effectively
than we
can yeah no doubt whatsoever um yeah so
again I think that that's a really
positive sentiment I'm really glad that
you raised it and I hope that people
that are watching that have been you
know maybe pissed off at myself and
others who have been critical of trump
on this stream I hope that they will be
fired up to go out and do exactly that
to raise their voices from that
conservative perspective but that is one
of the strengths of the unity4j vigils
is that we do openly welcome support
from from all all parts of the political
spectrum and let me say one more thing
about that too Elizabeth uh I was very
pessimistic for a long time and then
Jeff sessions left and so I think that
we've got a better chance now because
William bar is
a
functionary he's a a bureaucrat and a
paper pusher he's not an idealogue like
Jeff session was and so maybe perhaps
the guy might be willing to be
convinced we have to at least give it a
try completely agree completely agree uh
So based on that more um optimistic view
of of the president of the possibility
that he would change his mind uh what do
you see like can you just give maybe
maybe a kind of speculative forecast of
what you see happening in the future now
that we have now that Wikileaks has
exposed Ecuador's plans now that at
least right now they have an expelled
Assange from the embassy what do you see
happening going
forward that's one of the toughest
questions you've ever asked
me honestly I think it's so
fluid that anything could happen
and and we ought to we ought to treat
that as an
opportunity you know we ought to we
ought to be talking for example publicly
about the notion that Julian could
return to Australia or perhaps Julian
could go to Iceland or to Moscow or to
somebody mentioned Geneva the other day
uh
so I I think that it's it's really not
over until it's over I I think that
there are ideas that ought to be debated
publicly I think that Americans need to
be convinced that um that this ought not
to be a criminal
issue uh we need people to listen to the
argument that Dan ellberg has so
eloquently made for the for the last
several years that the Espionage Act is
unconstitutionally Broad and ought to be
challenged uh which it has not been and
so uh I I'll repeat myself I I think we
may have a we may have a a path to uh to
Justice
here that is an interesting point I I
can see what you're saying I really I
understand that in the sense that we're
looking at a at a field right now that
is more open than it's ever been in
multiple different ways whether it's as
you say the fact that uh Jeff sessions
is no longer the Attorney General the
fact that we you know there's this
instability in the government of lenon
Moreno and there is a pessimistic
outlook on that if you you know if you
consider the fact that lenon Moreno
could be replaced by somebody farther to
the right and more of a Lackey to the US
than Moreno already is yes but it's
still as you say it's still an
opportunity that everything is so fluid
right now in lots of different uh layers
of of the kind of context of all this I
think it is and Joe Lau is making a
point right now that that Rudy Giuliani
is apparently already making that
argument that this is a press issue not
a criminal issue and I I think that's
exactly right I can't believe I'm
agreeing with Rudy Jani exctly exactly
right this is a press issue listen I'm
gonna I'm going to sound like a broken
record again please let let's talk for
just a a couple of minutes about the
Espionage Act it's the it's the
Espionage Act of
197 this was an ACT written to combat
German sabots during the first world war
okay it is so old and so
outdated that that it doesn't even
mention the words classified
information it uses the term National
Defense information because when it was
written and updated the classification
system didn't even exist yet the
classification system was invented in
the mid1
1950s so that shows you how old this
thing is it is so broadly
written that in my view it's
unconstitutional it's so broadly written
that someone like Barack Obama can
charge eight whistleblowers with
Espionage for speaking to the
media well that wasn't the intent of the
Espionage Act the Espionage Act was
meant to punish people who were spying
for foreign
countries
well I think Julian's even more innocent
of Espionage than I was and all of my
Espionage charges were dropped because
clearly I hadn't committed Espionage
clearly Julian hasn't committed espion
this is indeed a press and media issue
that's the narrative that we need to
just keep hitting over and over and over
again this is not about Espionage it's
about press
Freedom absolutely and I think if if you
know in the pessimistic um you know
possibility of uh of Assange being not
only expelled extradited and prosecuted
but you know convicted you know that
would be and I think that's why it seems
like such an epic moment because that
would really present the prosecution and
the the conviction of the Free Press
because juliean and I I that's what I'm
asking you to comment on is that Julian
Assange is not just one person who was a
publisher a journalist who is unfairly
accused of Espionage and all these
different things he is as you said
earlier the most accurate publisher of
Our Generation if not ever so he
represents so much more than just
himself and Wikileaks and and if you can
please expand on that that would be
fantastic oh
yeah oh where do we even start with
something like you know I think the most
important point is that if Julian were
to be prosecuted
successfully that would open the door
for the justice department to prosecute
literally any journalist who
printed uh classified information in an
article it would
expose any news
Outlet uh including its Publishers to
espionage charges for publishing any
information that the government
considered to be National Defense or or
classified it would it would be the end
of a free press in the United States and
I really believe I'm not overstating
that that's how important this case is
as I said a half an hour ago this is one
of those once in a generation
cases that that our children are to be
reading about it history books and
that's why we have to get it
right absolutely and it's not just in
the country ac across the globe National
Security and international Affairs
journalists that are in those areas
would fear being prosecuted by the
United States because Assange is not an
American citizen and they would know
from that precedent that the First
Amendment would not extend to them in
the eyes of the US I mean that's right
and in addition to that in addition to
that you think the British government is
isn't watching this you think the French
aren't watching to see how this plays
out or the Israelis or even maybe the
Chinese everybody's going to see or are
looking they're looking to see if the
justice department can get away with
successfully Prosecuting a journalist on
an Espionage charge because I would bet
a paycheck if if this prosecution is
successful they're going to turn around
and do exactly the same
thing and in that sense it would be
almost you know the death of the
pretense of the West's ideals of
liberalism and you all of that that
we've grown up with those myths that we
have in childhood that the West believes
in that that would be the absolute um
implosion of that idea that's it
everything would
change and the prosecution of yourself
and others has shown that the
reality is not what we're told as far as
Justice in the US and all of that but I
think that what we would see is the
death of the pretense of those ideals I
guess um that's right you know there was
a that uh that received just about no
media coverage here in the US three
years
ago uh there was a woman who was a
journalist for the Washington times and
she was married to an official at the
Department of Education one morning at
6:00 AM uh armed federal agents broke
down the door of their house and seized
not just their computer but also files
now this was an armed SWAT team of the
Department of Education
so most Americans don't have any idea
that the Department of Education has an
armed SWAT team that will bust your door
down at six o'clock in the morning they
actually do as does the Environmental
Protection Agency and the Department of
Labor and other governmental
organizations the the dirty little
secret about federal law enforcement so
not only did they take this uh this
couple's computer saying that the
husband had um uh governmental
proprietary information on the computer
they took his wife's notes
she's a working journalist for the for
the Washington Times They took her notes
and they wouldn't give them back and so
there was no criminal prosecution at the
end of the day and then she had to sue
the government civil to recover her
notes a working
journalist now for whatever reason no
other journalist paid any attention in
this case and now here we are where a
journalist is being prosecuted
and and a journalistic entity is being
prosecuted well there's already kind of
a a precedent for seizing a journalist's
protected notes and the names of sources
so we have ourselves I mean not us on
this on this telecast but as Americans
we have ourselves to blame for not
putting our foot down when when these
rights began to be Whitted away and say
no we have constitutional protections we
didn't do that and now we find ourselves
in this
predicament yeah I think for myself and
maybe others you know growing up you
assume that those things just can't
happen and so when you don't hear about
them you assume that they're not
happening but yeah when something like
that happens and it's so
unconstitutional to such a huge degree
but they doesn't get press coverage you
know that really does go a long way to
continuing that false sense of I guess
security and safety um you know when I
was a kid I just goe always assumed that
um that adults
always knew what was best right they're
adults they they have educations and
they have experience and and they know
right from wrong and so they know what's
best and then you know by the time I was
an adult I was working on Capitol Hill
and I remember walking with a colleague
through the tunnel connecting the Senate
Russell office building to uh the capol
building and Mitch McConnell was walking
toward us and my colleague leaned over
and he said do you want to punch him or
should I and uh you know I that's kind
of an attitude that I've adopted here in
Washington I've lived in Washington for
37 years minus two for prison but uh but
that's that's that's my view now is
that we adults oftentimes don't know
what's best we don't know right from
wrong we act rationally not logically we
we act uh for short-term gain rather
than what's in the best interests of the
country and uh and that's got to stop
now of course it won't stop because it's
human nature so it's up to People Like
Us to ensure that it uh that it does as
little damage as possible this is one of
those unique opportunities that we can
actually do
good yeah and exactly and I think at we
at the very least we can shine a light
on that rash um you know action and that
the um you know inconsistent behavior
that we see happening um we have a few
minutes left is there anything else
you'd like to say to the audience or
just address in general that we haven't
uh discussed yet you know I'm going to
say say I I've been very fortunate to
have spoken with Julian a couple of
times over the phone but I've never met
the man in person uh that doesn't matter
to me one wit I am going to be out there
in the street I'm G to be writing about
this I'm going to go to the courthouse
if I have to take vacation time I'm
gonna go to the courthouse and to be
there and I encourage literally
everybody who is who is watching us
tonight to do the same thing we have to
stand together you know without without
that unity and that solidarity we have
nothing I I I completely
agree yeah Joey just asked uh asked John
who punched who punched Mitch McConnell
so he doesn't know how close he came
Joe but yeah no I think I think that's
an absolutely inspiring message though
and I think that that I mean I I myself
will have to travel to if expulsion and
arrest happens I'll travel to DC and
cover it myself and I would hope that
everyone else in the United States and
maybe internationally would join us in
doing that and and protesting I mean we
know that there is enough anger amongst
the populists at at this overall corrupt
plutocratic system whether they come at
it from a right-wing perspective or
leftwing perspective the public is angry
and in France for the yellow of us we're
seeing that persistent energy come to
that issue and we're seeing that uh as
you said you know in Venezuela we're
seeing the same thing we have have to
make that happen for julan Assange and
Wikileaks it's just not going to be
successful we do you know this this
comparison that you make to the yellow
vest I think is very appropriate uh I
heard somebody just recently described
the yellow vest movement as a leftist
movement it's not at all leftist um some
of them are leftists some of them are
rtists they're all Angry that's the
important thing and that that's us it
doesn't matter if you're approaching
this from the right or the left if
you're angry enough that that you
believe that Julian's son should not be
prosecuted then meet us at the
courthouse absolutely I couldn't agree
more and that's that is I exactly the
reason that I chose that comparison
because it is the exact same uh visceral
anger and bipartisanship that that is
motivating the yellow vest that needs to
motivate this movement for sure that's
right that's right we'll do it thank you
thank you John for joining us once again
it's always an honor and a pleasure to
speak with you go ahead pleasure is mine
happy to do it thank you and I'm sure we
will see you again and hopefully it will
continue to be in positive optimistic
circumstances right I look forward to
that thanks for having
[Music]